ergobaby.com 2018-12-26

# Ergobaby Privacy and Cookie Policy

_Last updated: March 11, 2013._

All digital extensions of the Ergobaby brand, such as Ergobaby.com, are known as the “Ergobaby Services.” The Ergobaby Services are owned and operated by The ERGObaby Carrier, Inc., its parent, its affiliates, agents and licensors (collectively, "we", "us", "our" or "Ergobaby").

Ergobaby is sensitive to your concerns about how we may use and share personal information that we collect from you through the Ergobaby Services, through the mail, and at retail stores and wholesale or distributor accounts. We respect your privacy and want to protect your personal information.

This Privacy Policy is incorporated into our Terms of Use and therefore governs your use of the Ergobaby Services and/or any services offered by Ergobaby. This Privacy Policy explains how we collect, use and (under certain conditions) disclose your personal information. This Privacy Policy also explains the steps we have taken to secure your personal information. Finally, this Privacy Policy explains your options regarding the collection, use and disclosure of your personal information. By visiting the Ergobaby Services, and/or utilizing any services offered by Ergobaby or through another Ergobaby Services, you accept the practices described in this Policy.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, please contact us at [support@ergobaby.com](mailto:support@ergobaby.com).

We are not responsible for the content or privacy practices on any websites not operated by Ergobaby Services to which Ergobaby Services link or that link to Ergobaby Services.

## **1.**  information collection and use

**1.1**  Information Collection.  
We collect information from you in several different ways on Ergobaby Services. One goal in collecting personal information from you is to provide an efficient, meaningful, and customized experience. For example, we can use your personal information to:

  * Help make the Ergobaby Services easier for you to use by not having to enter information more than once.
  * Help you quickly find information, products, and services.
  * Help us create and share content that is most relevant to you.
  * Alert you to new information, products, and services that we offer.

**1.2**  Registration and Ordering.  
Before using certain parts of any Ergobaby Services or ordering products, you may need to complete an online registration form. During registration, you will be prompted to provide to us certain personal information, including but not limited to your name, shipping and billing address(es), phone number, email address, and credit card number. In addition, we may also ask you for your country of residence and/or your organization’s country of operation, so we can comply with applicable laws and regulations, and for your gender. These kinds of personal information are used for billing purposes, to fulfill your orders, to communicate with you about your order and the Ergobaby Services, and for internal marketing purposes. If we encounter a problem when processing your order, your personal information may be used to contact you.

**1.3**  Email Addresses  
Several locations of the Ergobaby Services permit you to enter your email address for purposes including but not limited to: to register for a contest or sweepstakes; to request us to notify you of new products or styles or availability; to sign up for email newsletters and special offers. Your participation in a contest or sweepstakes is completely voluntary, so you have a choice whether to participate and disclose information to us. We use this information to notify contest and sweepstakes winners and to award prizes. We may post on the Ergobaby Services, as well as the Networks, the names and cities of contest and sweepstakes winners.  By entering a contest or sweepstakes, you may be opting in to receive our email newsletter and special offers and this will be disclosed in the official rules governing the contest or sweepstakes.

**1.4**  Cookies and Other Technology  
Like many Sites, the Ergobaby Services employs cookies and web beacons (also known as clear GIF technology or “action tags”) to speed your navigation of the Ergobaby Services, recognize you and your access privileges, and track your Ergobaby Services usage.

**1.4.1**  Cookies are small pieces of information that are stored as text files by your Internet browser on your computer’s hard drive. Most Internet browsers are initially set to accept cookies. You can set your browser to refuse cookies from web sites or to remove cookies from your hard drive, but if you do, you will not be able to access or use portions of the Ergobaby(R) Services. We have to use cookies to enable you to select products, place them in an online shopping cart, and to purchase those products. If you do this, we keep a record of your browsing activity and purchase. THE Ergobaby SERVICES’S COOKIES DO NOT AND CANNOT INFILTRATE A USER’S HARD DRIVE TO GATHER A USER’S CONFIDENTIAL INFORMATION. Our cookies are not “spyware.”

**1.4.2.  **Web beacons assist in delivering cookies and help us determine whether a web page on the Ergobaby Services has been viewed and, if so, how many times. For example, any electronic image on the Ergobaby Services, such as an ad banner, can function as a web beacon.

**1.4.3.  **We may use third-party advertising companies to help tailor Ergobaby Services content to users or to serve ads on our behalf. These companies may employ cookies and web beacons to measure advertising effectiveness (such as which web pages are visited or what products are purchased and in what amount). Any information that these third parties collect via cookies and web beacons is not linked to any personal information collected by us.

**1.4.4.  **As an example, Facebook collects certain information via cookies and web beacons to determine which web pages are visited or what products are purchased. Please note that any information collected by Facebook via cookies and web beacons is not linked to any customer's personal information collected by us.

**1.5**  Log Files.  
As is true of most websites, the Ergobaby Services servers automatically recognizes the Internet URL from which you access the Ergobaby Services. We may also log your Internet protocol (“IP”) address, Internet service provider, and date/time stamp for system administration, order verification, internal marketing, and system troubleshooting purposes. (An IP address may indicate the location of your computer on the Internet.)

**1.6**  Age.  
We respect children’s privacy. We do not knowingly or intentionally collect personal information from children under age 18. Elsewhere on the Ergobaby Services, you have represented and warranted that you are either 18 years of age or using the Ergobaby Services with the supervision of a parent or guardian. If you are under the age of 18, please do not submit any personal information to us, and rely on a parent or guardian to assist you.

**1.7**  Product Reviews.  
You may choose to submit a product review. If you post a review, we will ask for your email address and geographic location. If you submit a review, your geographic location will be visible to other users (your email address will be kept private). Also, any personally identifiable information that you submit as part of the review can be read or used by other visitors to the Ergobaby Services. We are not responsible for any personally identifiable information that you choose to submit as part of your review. We believe you can post a helpful review without disclosing any personal information.

**1.8**  Geographic Location.  
Ergobaby Services may use the GPS feature of your mobile device to determine your geographic location. This information is used to provide you with the address of -- and directions to -- the nearest store location with Ergobaby or other location-dependent features. If you would prefer that we not know your geographic location, you may disable or decline the function when you first use any of the Ergobaby Services, respectively (or later, if your mobile device allows you to change the settings after initial download). Disabling the geolocation function may prevent you from using certain features of the Ergobaby Services (such as the store locator) that require such information.

## **2.**  information use and disclosure

**2.1**  Internal Use.  
We use your personal information to process your order and provide you with customer service. We may internally use your personal information to improve the Ergobaby Services content and layout, to improve outreach and for our own marketing efforts (including marketing our services and products to you), and to determine general marketplace information about visitors to the Ergobaby Services. In order to facilitate such use and the other use described in this Section 2, we may share your information with affiliates under Ergobaby’s control.

**2.2**  Communications with You:  
We will use your personal information to communicate with you about the Ergobaby Services and your orders and deliveries. Also, we may send you a confirmation email when you register with us. We may send you a service-related announcement on the rare occasions when it is necessary (for example, if we must temporarily suspend our service for maintenance.) Also, you may submit your email address for to register for a contest or sweepstakes; to request us to notify you of new products or styles or availability; to sign up for email newsletters and special offers. If you submit your email address, we use it to deliver the information to you. We always permit you to unsubscribe or opt out of future emails (see the opt out section, below, for more details). Because we have to communicate with you about orders that you choose to place, you cannot opt out of receiving emails related to your orders.

**2.3**  External Use.  
We want to provide you with excellent service and to offer you a great selection. We do not sell, rent, trade, license or otherwise disclose your specific personal information or financial information to anyone other than to affiliates under Ergobaby’s control, except that:

**2.3.1.  **As do most catalog and Internet retailers, we sometimes use others to perform specific functions on our behalf. When we disclose information to these service providers, we disclose information to help them to perform their service. For example, in order to deliver products to you, we must share some information. We partner with third parties (such as the United Parcel Service) to ship products, to ensure delivery, and so that we can obtain feedback, improve the quality of our service, and measure and improve the quality of the service of the third party. In the example of shippers, we provide them some personally identifiable information such as your name, shipping address, email, and phone number.

**2.3.2.  **Similarly, to help you buy products and provide customer service to you, we must provide your credit card number to financial-services corporations such as credit-card processors and issuers. When we submit your credit card number for authorization, we use state-of-the-art data encryption to protect your information. (More on this below in Data Security.)

**2.3.3.  **We may disclose such information in response to requests from law enforcement officials conducting investigations; subpoenas; a court order; or if we are otherwise required to disclose such information by law. We also will release personal information where disclosure is necessary to protect our legal rights, enforce our Terms of Use or other agreements, or to protect ourselves or others. For example, we may share information to reduce the risk of fraud or if someone uses or attempts to use the Ergobaby Services for illegal reasons or to commit fraud.

**2.3.4.  **We will not sell (or trade or rent) personally identifiable information to other companies as part of our regular course of business. However, it’s possible that we might acquire or merge with or be acquired by another company or that we might dispose of some or all of our assets. If that happens, your personal information may be disclosed to another company, but that disclosure will be subject to the Privacy Policy in effect.

**2.3.5.  **We may share non-personal information (such as the number of daily visitors to a particular web page, or the size of an order placed on a certain date) with third parties such as advertising partners. This information does not directly personally identify you or any user.

**2.3.6.  **We may publicly disclose the name, city, and state of the contest and sweepstakes winners.

## **3.**  data security

The Ergobaby Services incorporate physical, electronic, and administrative procedures to safeguard the confidentiality of your personal information, including Secure Sockets Layer (“SSL”) for all financial transactions through the Ergobaby Services. We use SSL encryption to protect your personal information online, and we also take several steps to protect your personal information in our facilities. Access to your personal information is restricted. Only employees who need access to your personal information to perform a specific job are granted access to your personal information. Finally, we rely on third-party service providers for the physical security of some of our computer hardware. We believe that their security procedures are adequate. For example, when you visit the Ergobaby Services, you access servers that are kept in a secure physical environment, behind a locked cage and an electronic firewall.

While we use industry-standard precautions to safeguard your personal information, we cannot guarantee complete security. 100% complete security does not presently exist anywhere online or offline.

## **4.**  opt out/corrections

Upon your request, we will (1) correct or update your personal information; (2) stop sending emails to your email address; and/or (3) disable your account to prevent any future purchases through that account. You can make these requests at the customer information section of the Ergobaby Services: http://www.Ergobaby.com/cs, or by telephoning, or emailing your request to Ergobaby’s Customer Care Team 888-416-4888 or: [support@ergobaby.com](mailto:support@ergobaby.com) Please do not email your credit-card number or other sensitive information.

## **5.**  offline collection, use & disclosure of information

As you might expect from us, the majority of information that we collect is obtained through the Ergobaby Services, and this Privacy Policy applies only to that online collection of personal information. We also may collect information offline, where we also try to protect the privacy of your personal information. One example involves someone calling us to place an order or to ask questions. When someone calls, we will ask only for the personal information we need in order to place the order or to answer the question. When we need to store information (such as order information), we will enter it into our database through SSL encryption. (See the Data Security section above for more information). Another example involves faxes. If you fax something to us, we will act upon the fax and then either store it a locked repository or we will shred the fax if there is no need to retain the information. There are other ways we could learn of personal information offline (for example, we suppose someone could send us a letter including some return address information), and this Policy doesn’t discuss or try to predict all of those methods or uses. As we mentioned, we will try to treat offline collection, uses, and disclosures consistently with our relevant online practices. External Links: If any part of the Ergobaby Services links you to other Web sites or mobile applications, those Web sites and mobile applications do not operate under this privacy policy. We recommend that you examine the privacy statements posted on those other Web sites and mobile applications to understand their procedures for collecting, using, and disclosing personal information.

## **6.**  updates to this policy

If we change or update this Privacy Policy, we will post changes and updates on the Ergobaby Services so that you will always be aware of what information we collect, use and disclose. We encourage you to review this Privacy Policy from time to time so you will know if the Privacy Policy has been changed or updated. If you have any questions about the Privacy Policy, please contact us at 888-416-4888 or [support@ergobaby.com](mailto:support@ergobaby.com).
